<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ECON03SEC1s on econ03sec1</title>
    <link>/econ03sec1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ECON03SEC1s on econ03sec1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/econ03sec1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 1: Basics of Excel</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-1-basicsofexcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-1-basicsofexcel/</guid>
      <description>We shall use Microsoft Excel 2013 during the course. So I would suggest the class to install the 2013 version in their computers.Go through the syllabus uploaded in the university website.The references are given in the syllabus. In addition, go through the book Microsoft Excel 2013: Data Analysis and Business Modeling by Wayne L. Winston.1.1 Introduction1.2 Few other ‘must know’ things before you begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 2: Data Management</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-2-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-2-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Contents2.1 Data transformation 2.2 Importing and editing data from text files/documents
2.3 Creating named ranges
2.4 IF() statement
2.5 The COUNTIF(), COUNTIFS(), COUNT(), COUNTA(), and COUNTBLANK() functions
2.6 The SUMIF(), AVERAGEIF(), SUMIFS(), and AVERAGEIFS() functions
2.7 Sorting
2.8 Filtering and removing duplicates
2.9 Lookup functions
2.1 Data transformationIn this lecture we shall cover: Data transformation: arithmetic operation- addition, subtraction, multiplication, log transformation, exponential, squaring and square root, indices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 3: Descriptive Statistics</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-3-descriptive-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-3-descriptive-stats/</guid>
      <description>Contents3.1 Univariate data
3.2 Multivariate data
3.1 Univariate dataIn this lecture video we shall cover the Measures of Central Tendency, Measures of Dispersion, treatment of outliers,rank with and without ties, and Moments and Order Statistics.
In the above video i.e. Part 2, please note that the explanation for TRIMMEAN() function will hold true only if I had sorted the data in ascending or descending form. Else the explanation is that trim mean is calculated by deleting the x number of highest and the lowest values, and NOT the top or bottom values in an un-sorted/any random data series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 4: Optimisation</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-4-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-4-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>This module will deal with optimisation problem using the Solver plugin in Excel.
Download the file Prodmix.xlsx used in the video and practice.Exercises:Suppose your drug company can purchase up to 500 hours of labor at $1 more per hour than current labor costs. How can it maximize profit?
At a chip manufacturing plant, four technicians (A, B, C, and D) produce three products (Products 1, 2, and 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 5: Graphical Presentation of Data</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-5-graphicalpresentationofdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-5-graphicalpresentationofdata/</guid>
      <description>Contents5.1 Histograms
5.2 Graphs
5.1 HistogramsIn this section we shall learn to graph a histogram. A histogram is a commonly used tool to summarise data. It tells you how many observations/data points falls in various ranges of values.
Download and practice the file used in the video.Exercises:Use the data in Stock.xlsx to construct histograms for monthly returns for GE and Intel.Use the data in Historicalinvest2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 6: Empirical Project 1</title>
      <link>/econ03sec1/module-6-empirical-project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03sec1/module-6-empirical-project-1/</guid>
      <description>This project is based on the content and materials of (www.core-econ.org) 
Project: The behaviour of average surface temperature over timeIn this project we shall consider the data from NASA about land-ocean temperature anomalies in the northern hemisphere. Figure 1 is constructed using this data and shows temperatures in northern hemisphere over the period 1880-2019, expressed as differences from the average temperature from 1951-1980.
Figure 1: Average temperature anomalyGo to NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>